<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>DustyCloud Brainstorms</title><link href="http://dustycloud.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://dustycloud.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://dustycloud.org/</id><updated>2015-05-01T21:55:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Interviewed on Ryno the Bearded</title><link href="http://dustycloud.org/blog/rynothebearded-interview/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-07T20:04:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Christopher Allan Webber</name></author><id>tag:dustycloud.org,2015-04-07:blog/rynothebearded-interview/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://rynothebearded.com/2015/04/my-origin-story/"&gt;interviewed on Ryno the Bearded&lt;/a&gt;
in an episode with the curious title &amp;quot;My Origin Story&amp;quot;.  I'm not sure
whose that refers to, maybe both of us, because we both talked about
our backstories.  (Though, I think if I was going to lay out my &amp;quot;free
software origin story&amp;quot;, it would probably include some other
things... but maybe it would get to be fairly rambly.  I've thought
about trying to write up what that is before, but I guess there were a
lot of &amp;quot;moments&amp;quot; for my free software origins, not any one moment like
&amp;quot;I was bitten by a libre radioactive spider&amp;quot;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed doing this one, and maybe you'll enjoy listening to
it.  It's kind of rambly and conversational and we came in with very
little as in terms of questions, but I think I tend to do fairly well
in that format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did cut off the end of the interview by saying I had to go to the
bathroom though.  Not really the most dignified of exits on my part.
Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="ryno the bearded"></category><category term="podcast"></category><category term="interview"></category><category term="mediagoblin"></category></entry><entry><title>Fever Dream: cryptocurrency</title><link href="http://dustycloud.org/blog/fever-dream-cryptocurrency/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-29T12:42:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Christopher Allan Webber</name></author><id>tag:dustycloud.org,2015-03-29:blog/fever-dream-cryptocurrency/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been sick the last two days, and for some reason, I've been
dreaming in lisp.  It's not the first time I've dreamt in code, but
all times have been in lisp.  Maybe lisp is not as readable as many
would like, but it seems dreamable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just got up from another nap, another lisp-based fever dream. This one
about a cryptocurrencty on an actor model system, built for a MUD/AR
type environment... no blockchain required (note: may be inspired by
reading Rainbows End between naps):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various actors represent &amp;quot;reserves&amp;quot;, like the Federal Reserve can
print their own money, as much as they like, but there may be
various community enforcements of this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You might have different central banks / reserves on different
servers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;quot;value&amp;quot; or exchange rate determined by the market, like
international currency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currency is non-divisible (you have 100 rupees, but not .1 rupees)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bank has a private key, so does each actor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basically more or less passing along capabilities (I think???) but
maybe even the central bank signing whoever has &amp;quot;posession&amp;quot;. The
bank does not know who things are transferred to, but does verify
that the transferring owner has the right capability currently
belonging to that unit's ID, and does issue a new capability to the
new owner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this make sense? I'm too sick to know for now. But transactions
flying everywhere, wrapped in parentheses, in my fevered mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I have more crazy lisp fever dreams today I will record them here.
No guarantee of sanity.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="cryptocurrency"></category><category term="fever"></category></entry></feed>
